Guide to the M. Glen Johnson Papers, 1967-1986
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
M. Glen Johnson Papers
1967-1986
Johnson, Maurice Glen, 1936-
0.5 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, minutes, and reports relating to Johnson's committee work as a member of the faculty at Vassar College
Biographical Note
Received his A.B. from Georgetown College, and his M.A and PhD. from the University of North Carolina. Taught at the University of North Carolina and the University of Kentucky before becoming a faculty member in the Political Science Department of Vassar College in 1964. He chaired the department from 1974-1977. He has also served in a number of of administrative positions, such as Dean of Freshmen, Assistant to the President, Assistant Dean of Studies, and twice as Acting President (1997-1998, 2003-2004).
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, minutes, and reports relating to Johnson's committee work as a member of the faculty at Vassar College.
Access
Folders 2.7 and 2.8 are restricted. The rest of this collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College. General Education Committee; Vassar College. Committee on New Dimensions
VCL Categories
Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, January 2009.
Acquisition Information
Gift of M. Glen Johnson, August 2000.
Container List
- Advisory Group on Coeducation, 1984 (Folder 1.1)
- Tenure, 1974-1983 (Folder 1.2)
- Tenure [Research] Materials, 1973-1975 (Folder 1.3)
- FASC [Faculty Appointments and Salary Committee] Sufferage, 1983 (Folder 1.4)
- East Asian Major, 1973 (Folder 1.5)
- Task Force on General Education and the Freshman Year, 1980 (Folder 1.6)
- Tenure Question, 1973-1984 (Folder 1.7)
- Presidential Review, 1976-1985 (Folder 1.8)
- Simpson Retirement and VBS Retirement, 1976-1977, 1986 (Folder 1.9)
- Committee on New Dimensions, ca. 1967 (Folder 2.1)
- FPCC, Faculty Policy and Conference Committee, 1974- 1975 (Folder 2.2)
- General Education Task Force Report, 1980 (Folder 2.3)
- General Education Committee, 1978-1980 (Folder 2.4)
- General Education Committee, ca. 1980 (Folder 2.5)
- Overview Committee Report, 1979-1980 (Folder 2.6)
- Chaplain - Stokes [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Folder 2.7)
- Chaplancy [RESTRICTED], 1979-1980 (Folder 2.8)